<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="no"?>

<modDesc descVersion="80">
    <title>
        <en>Shelter Matters</en>
    </title>
    <description>
        <en><![CDATA[
ShelterMatters enhances the importance of sheds and indoor storage in Farming Simulator 22 by introducing realistic wear and decay mechanics. Vehicles, tools, and stored goods deteriorate faster when exposed to the elements, making proper storage essential. Products now have a best-before period, after which they begin to degrade. Factors like moisture and temperature further influence their lifespan, requiring players to manage storage conditions carefully. Proper shelter is no longer just optional - it is key to efficiently preserving your equipment and produce, adding to a more immersive farming experience.

# Features

- Vehicle & Tool Degradation: Outdoor exposure causes gradual damage to unused vehicles and equipment
- Perishable Goods System:
  - Best-by dates
  - Weather wetness (rain/snow causes moisture damage)
  - Temperature effects (heat spoilage, freezing damage)
- Smart Storage Detection:
  - Automatic recognition of valid indoor spaces
  - Custom zone markers for non-standard structures (found in Buildings - Sheds)
- Customizable Settings:
  - Adjustable decay rates via config files
  - Savegame-specific configurations

https://github.com/depuits/FS22_ShelterMatters/releases/

Changelog v1.2.0.0

- Pallet & Trailer Goods Decay: Stored products in pallets and trailers now decay over time based on environmental factors.
  - Wetness sensitive products exposed to rain accumulate moisture, increasing decay rate by wetness.
  - Temperature sensitive products have a minimum and maximum temperature range within which they remain stable. Outside this range, they will decay.
  - Shelf life limited products have a best-before date. Before expiry, they remain intact, but after, they begin to decay at a fixed rate.
- Bale Decay Reworked: Bales now follow the same decay mechanics as pallets, making storage management more consistent and realistic.

Changelog v1.1.2.0

- Display of bale decay in infobox

Changelog v1.1.1.0

- Added Indoor Area placeables under Buildings → Sheds for improved indoor detection

Changelog v1.1.0.0

- Added bale deterioration when left outside in the rain
        ]]></en>
        <de><![CDATA[
ShelterMatters unterstreicht die Bedeutung von Schuppen und Lagerhallen im Landwirtschafts-Simulator 22 durch die Einführung realistischer Verschleiß- und Verfallsmechanismen. Fahrzeuge, Werkzeuge und gelagerte Waren verschlechtern sich schneller, wenn sie den Elementen ausgesetzt sind, weshalb eine ordnungsgemäße Lagerung unerlässlich ist. Produkte haben nun ein Mindesthaltbarkeitsdatum, nach dem sie zu verfallen beginnen. Faktoren wie Feuchtigkeit und Temperatur beeinflussen ihre Lebensdauer zusätzlich, sodass Spieler die Lagerbedingungen sorgfältig steuern müssen. Ein guter Unterstand ist nicht länger nur optional – er ist entscheidend für die effiziente Konservierung Ihrer Geräte und Produkte und trägt zu einem noch intensiveren landwirtschaftlichen Erlebnis bei.

# Funktionen

- Fahrzeug- und Werkzeugverschleiß: Im Freien verursacht er allmählichen Schaden an ungenutzten Fahrzeugen und Geräten.
- Verderbliches Warensystem:
    - Mindesthaltbarkeitsdaten
    - Nässe (Regen/Schnee verursacht Feuchtigkeitsschäden)
    - Temperatureffekte (Hitzeschäden, Frostschäden)
- Intelligente Lagererkennung:
    - Automatische Erkennung gültiger Innenräume
    - Benutzerdefinierte Zonenmarkierungen für nicht standardmäßige Strukturen (zu finden unter Gebäude – Schuppen)
- Anpassbare Einstellungen:
    - Einstellbare Verfallsraten über Konfigurationsdateien
    - Spielstandspezifische Konfigurationen

https://github.com/depuits/FS22_ShelterMatters/releases/

Changelog v1.2.0.0

- Verfall von Paletten- und Anhängergütern: Gelagerte Produkte auf Paletten und Anhängern verderben nun mit der Zeit aufgrund von Umweltfaktoren.
    - Feuchtigkeitsempfindliche Produkte, die Regen ausgesetzt sind, sammeln Feuchtigkeit an, wodurch die Verfallsrate durch Nässe steigt.
    - Temperaturempfindliche Produkte haben einen minimalen und maximalen Temperaturbereich, innerhalb dessen sie stabil bleiben. Außerhalb dieses Bereichs verderben sie.
    - Produkte mit begrenzter Haltbarkeit haben ein Mindesthaltbarkeitsdatum. Vor Ablauf des Verfallsdatums bleiben sie intakt, danach beginnen sie jedoch mit einer festgelegten Rate zu verderben.
- Ballenverfall überarbeitet: Ballen unterliegen nun der gleichen Verfallsmechanik wie Paletten, wodurch die Lagerverwaltung konsistenter und realistischer wird.

Changelog v1.1.2.0

- Anzeige des Ballenverfalls in der Infobox

Changelog v1.1.1.0

- Platzierbare Objekte für Innenbereiche unter Gebäude → Schuppen hinzugefügt, um die Erkennung von Innenräumen zu verbessern

Changelog v1.1.0.0

- Verschlechterung der Ballenqualität hinzugefügt, wenn sie im Regen draußen stehen gelassen werden
        ]]></de>
        <fr><![CDATA[
ShelterMatters renforce l'importance des hangars et des entrepôts dans Farming Simulator 22 en introduisant des mécanismes d'usure et de dégradation réalistes. Les véhicules, les outils et les marchandises entreposées se détériorent plus rapidement lorsqu'ils sont exposés aux éléments, ce qui rend un stockage adéquat essentiel. Les produits ont désormais une date limite de consommation, après laquelle ils commencent à se dégrader. Des facteurs comme l'humidité et la température influencent également leur durée de vie, obligeant les joueurs à gérer soigneusement les conditions de stockage. Un abri adéquat n'est plus une option : il est essentiel pour préserver efficacement votre équipement et vos produits, contribuant ainsi à une expérience agricole plus immersive.

# Fonctionnalités

- Dégradation des véhicules et des outils: L’exposition à l’extérieur endommage progressivement les véhicules et équipements non utilisés.
- Système de denrées périssables:
    - Dates limites de consommation
    - Humidité due aux intempéries (pluie/neige)
    - Effets de la température (détérioration par la chaleur, dommages dus au gel)
- Détection intelligente du stockage:
    - Reconnaissance automatique des espaces intérieurs valides
    - Marqueurs de zone personnalisés pour les structures non standard (disponibles dans Bâtiments - Abris)
- Paramètres personnalisables:
    - Taux de dégradation ajustables via les fichiers de configuration
    - Configurations spécifiques aux sauvegardes

https://github.com/depuits/FS22_ShelterMatters/releases/

Changelog v1.2.0.0

- Dégradation des produits sur palettes et remorques: Les produits stockés sur palettes et remorques se dégradent désormais avec le temps en fonction des facteurs environnementaux.
    - Les produits sensibles à l'humidité exposés à la pluie accumulent de l'humidité, ce qui augmente leur taux de dégradation.
    - Les produits thermosensibles ont une plage de températures minimale et maximale dans laquelle ils restent stables. En dehors de cette plage, ils se dégradent.
    - Les produits à durée de conservation limitée ont une date limite de consommation. Avant leur péremption, ils restent intacts, mais après, ils commencent à se dégrader à un rythme fixe.
- Dégradation des balles repensée: Les balles suivent désormais le même mécanisme de dégradation que les palettes, ce qui rend la gestion du stockage plus cohérente et plus réaliste.

Changelog v1.1.2.0

- Affichage de la décomposition des balles dans l'infobox

Changelog v1.1.1.0

- Ajout d'éléments de zone intérieure sous Bâtiments → Remises pour une meilleure détection intérieure

Changelog v1.1.0.0

- Ajout de la détérioration des balles lorsqu'elles sont laissées à l'extérieur sous la pluie
        ]]></fr>
    </description>
    <author>Depuits</author>
    <version>dev</version>

    <iconFilename>icon_ShelterMatters.dds</iconFilename>
    <multiplayer supported="true"/>

    <l10n filenamePrefix="translations/translation"/>

    <extraSourceFiles>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMatters.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersHelpers.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersSyncEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersBale.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersBaleDecayedEvent.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersIndoorDetection.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersObjectDecayFunctions.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/shelterMattersDefaultRules.lua"/>
        <sourceFile filename="src/injectSpecialization.lua"/>
    </extraSourceFiles>

    <specializations>
        <specialization name="shelterMattersObjectDecay" className="ShelterMattersObjectDecay" filename="src/shelterMattersObjectDecay.lua"/>
    </specializations>

    <placeableSpecializations>
        <specialization name="shelterMattersIndoorArea" className="ShelterMattersIndoorArea" filename="src/shelterMattersIndoorArea.lua"/>
        <specialization name="shelterMattersSiloDecay" className="ShelterMattersSiloDecay" filename="src/shelterMattersSiloDecay.lua"/>
    </placeableSpecializations>

    <placeableTypes>
        <type name="shelterMattersIndoorArea" parent="simplePlaceable" filename="$dataS/scripts/placeables/Placeable.lua">
            <specialization name="shelterMattersIndoorArea" />
        </type>
    </placeableTypes>

    <storeItems>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaSquare5x5.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaSquare10x10.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaSquare25x25.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaSquare50x50.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaRectangle5x10.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaRectangle5x25.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaRectangle10x25.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaRectangle10x50.xml"/>
        <storeItem xmlFilename="indoorAreas/indoorAreaRectangle25x50.xml"/>
    </storeItems>
</modDesc>
